

Summary_

I am currently studying my PhD at the University of Victoria, Wellington while also working as a Senior Data Scientist at New Zealand's national statistics agency (Statistics NZ). My main line of research in my PhD investigates changes in authoritarian under varying levels of threat due to COVID-19. Through my research and current work commitments, I have a broad range of experience in statistical methods including structural equation modeling, multi-level modeling, and Bayesian methods.

Employment _____

Statistics New Zealand Senior Data Scientist	2019 - Present
University of Otago Assistant Research Fellow	2019 - 2020
Te Runanga o Ngai Tahu Statistician	2018 - 2019
Statistics New Zealand Statistical Analyst	2016 - 2019
University of Otago Senior Research Assistant	2013 - 2016
Queensland Department of Natural Resources and Mines PROJECT OFFICER	2013 - 2015
University of Otago RESEARCH ASSISTANT	2012 - 2014

Education _____

Victoria University of Wellington	Wellington
Doctor of Philosophy	Present
University of Otago	Dunedin
MASTER OF SCIENCE	2016

Awards and scholarships ______

2018	IPANZ Young Professional Of The Year (Top 3)	Administration NZ
2018	Victoria Doctoral Scholarship	Victoria University of Wellington
2015	Otago Research Master's Scholarship	University of Otago

Institute of Public

Publications _____

- 1. Winter, T, P Jose, B Riordan, B Bizumic, T Ruffman, J Hunter, and D Scarf (In Review). Left-wing support of authoritarian submission to protect against societal threat. *Political Psychology*.
- 2. Riordan, B, T Winter, J Flett, D Scarf, P Jose, and T Conner (In Review). Does the Fear of Missing Out (FoMO) moderate the relationship between social networking use and affect? A daily diary study. *Computers in Human Behavior*.

- 3. Winter, T, B Riordan, A Surace, D Scarf, and P Jose (2020). A tutorial on the use of informative Bayesian priors for minority research.
- 4. Winter, T, T Conner, and P Jose (Accepted). Methodological and conceptual complexities of assessing relationships between single-occasion CRP inflammation and daily affect. *Brain, Behavior, and Immunity Health*.
- 5. Zimmerman, H, B Riordan, T Winter, A Bartonicek, and D Scarf (Accepted). Are New Zealand psychology students more susceptible to essentialist explanations for mental illness? Neuroessentialism and mental illness stigma in psychology and non-psychology students. *New Zealand Journal of Psychology*.
- 6. Scarf, D, T Winter, B Riordan, J Hunter, K Tustin, M Gollop, N Taylor, J Kokaua, and R Poulton (Accepted). A longitudinal study of mental wellbeing in students that transition into PhD study. *Frontiers in Psychology*.
- 7. Raubenheimer, JE, BC Riordan, JE Merrill, T Winter, RM Ward, D Scarf, and NA Buckley (2021). Hey Google! will New Zealand vote to legalise cannabis? Using Google Trends data to predict the outcome of the 2020 New Zealand cannabis referendum. *International Journal of Drug Policy*.
- 8. Winter, T, B Riordan, A Pakpour, M Griffiths, A Mason, J Poulgrain, and D Scarf (2020). Evaluation of the English version of the Fear of COVID-19 Scale and its relationship with behavior change and political beliefs. *International Journal of Mental Health and Addiction*.
- 9. Riordan, BC, J Raubenheimer, RM Ward, JE Merrill, T Winter, and D Scarf (2020). Monitoring the sentiment of cannabis-related tweets in the lead up to New Zealand's cannabis referendum. *Drug and Alcohol Review*.
- 10. Scarf, D, H Zimmerman, T Winter, H Boden, S Graham, BC Riordan, and JA Hunter (Apr. 2020). Association of Viewing the Films Joker or Terminator: Dark Fate With Prejudice Toward Individuals With Mental Illness. *JAMA Network Open*.
- 11. Graham, S, A Mason, B Riordan, T Winter, and D Scarf (Dec. 2020). Taking a Break from Social Media Improves Wellbeing Through Sleep Quality. *Cyberpsychology, Behavior, and Social Networking*.
- 12. Winter, T, T Conner, and P Jose (2020). Identifying Profiles of Affective Change: An Ecological Momentary Assessment of Flourishers. *Emotion*.
- 13. Trevis, KJ, E McTavish, T Winter, Y Fu, J McTavish, B Wilson, J Oliver, and EA Franz (2019). Harnessing the Brain's Neuro-Compensatory Processes: Lessons from a High-Functioning Person with Complete Agenesis of the Corpus Callosum. *Neuropsychologie clinique et appliquée*.
- 14. Winter, T, B Riordan, and A Surace (2019). The relationship between hazardous alcohol use and discrimination among Māori in Aotearoa New Zealand. *Addiction*.
- 15. Surace, A, B Riordan, and T Winter (2019). Do New Zealand sexual minorities engage in more hazardous drinking than non-sexual minorities? *Drug and Alcohol Review*.
- 16. Pittar, N, T Winter, L Falland-Cheung, D Tong, and J Waddell (2018). Scalp simulation A novel approach to site-specific biomechanical modeling of the skin. *Journal of the Mechanical Behavior of Biomedical Materials*.
- 17. Falland-Cheung, L, JN Waddell, MS Lazarjan, MC Jermy, T Winter, D Tong, and PA Brunton (2017). Use of agar/glycerol and agar/glycerol/water as a translucent brain simulant for ballistic testing. *Journal of the Mechanical Behavior of Biomedical Materials*.
- 18. Franz, EA, Y Fu, M Moore, T Winter, T Mayne, R Debnath, and C Stringer (2016). Fooling the brain by mirroring the hand: brain correlates of the perceptual capture of limb ownership. *Restorative neurology and neuroscience*.
- 19. Tong, D, T Winter, J Jin, A Bennett, and J Waddell (2015). Quantification of subconcussive impact forces to the head using a forensic model. *Journal of Clinical Neuroscience*.
- 20. Winter, TJ and EA Franz (2014). Implication of the anterior commissure in the allocation of attention to action. *Frontiers in Psychology*.

Presentations and posters

Authoritarian submission on the left and right during the covid-19 pandemic in New Zealand New Zealand Psychological Society Conference, Wellington Using overseas surveys to produce reliable models of sexual minorities New Zealand Population Conference, Wellington Alcohol use disparities among gender and sexual minorities in New Zealand (Poster) Collaborative Perspectives on Addiction, Rhode Island Iwi data tool using integrated data and R Shiny Iwi Data Conference, Christchurch

Using data to support a collective impact model of Maori potential Population Association of New Zealand Conference, Christchurch	2016
The effect of motherhood on income	2016
New Zealand Association of Economists conference, Wellington	
A machine learning approach to classifying life course outcomes	2016
Longitudinal and multivariate analysis network (Stats NZ), Wellington	
Methodology for comparing incomes between parents and non-parents Statistical methods seiminar (Stats NZ), Wellington	2016
Inter-hemispheric inhibition in the autistic brain Neuroethics seminar, Dunedin	2014

Skills_

- Health psychology research
- Social psychology research
- Research design and analysis
- Structural equation modelling and causal analysis
- Bayesian statistics and multi-level modelling
- Machine learning techniques such as random forests and neural nets
- Teaching reproducible research practices and statistics
- Knowledge of Tikanga Māori